Hello everyone and welcome to EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎收听EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
My name is Catherine.
我是Catherine。
And today we're doing something that makes a lot of people very nervous when they come
今天我们聊的话题，让很多人来
to America.
美国时都会很紧张。
That's right.
没错。
Today we are arriving to the airport, but before we can leave, we need to pass through
今天我们到达机场，但在离开之前，我们需要通过
customs and immigration.
海关和移民检查。
All right.
好的。
Customs and immigration.
海关和移民检查。
So anyone who comes into the United States, American, not American, doesn't matter, you
所以任何进入美国的人，不管是不是美国人，都一样，你
have to go through this gate.
必须经过这道关卡。
So let's learn about some of these phrases and questions in today's dialogue.
那么，让我们通过今天的对话来学习一些相关的短语和问题。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Passport and arrival card, please.
请出示护照和入境卡。
Here you are.
给你。
Where are you coming from?
你从哪里来？
China.
中国。
Is this your country of birth or residence?
这是你的出生国或居住国吗？
I just worked there.
我只是在那里工作。
What is the purpose of your visit to the United States?
你来美国的目的是什么？
I'm here on vacation.
我来度假。
How long do you plan to stay in the United States?
你计划在美国待多久？
Almost three weeks.
差不多三周。
Sir, you didn't fill out the information on your arrival card of where you'll be staying.
先生，你没有填写入境卡上关于你住宿地点的信息。
Oh, I'm sorry, but there are a couple of different places I will travel to within the United
哦，对不起，但我在美国会去几个不同的地方旅行，
States, so I wasn't sure what to put.
所以我不确定该填什么。
You must specify an address on the place where you will spend most of your time.
你必须指定一个地址，是你大部分时间待的地方。
Okay.
好的。
Here you are.
给你。
Do you have enough means to support yourself while you're here?
你在这里期间有足够的经济来源支持自己吗？
Yes, I have some travelers checks and two credit cards.
是的，我有一些旅行支票和两张信用卡。
Very good.
很好。
Do you have anything to declare?
你有什么要申报的吗？
Nope.
没有。
I only have my clothes and camera.
我只有衣服和相机。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Welcome to the United States.
欢迎来到美国。
Enjoy your visit.
祝您旅途愉快。
All right, we're back.
好了，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of that language takeaway.
现在让我们看看一些语言要点。
Language takeaway.
语言要点。
The first thing we have to learn about is the arrival card.
我们要学的第一件事是入境卡。
So good afternoon, passport and arrival card, please.
所以，下午好，请出示护照和入境卡。
That's the first line of the dialogue.
这是对话的第一行。
That's right.
没错。
So the arrival card, usually you will get on the airplane before you land, and basically
所以入境卡，通常你会在飞机降落前拿到，基本上
you just have to put your name, your passport number, where you're from, and basic information
你只需要填上姓名、护照号码、来自哪里，以及类似的基本信息，
like this that you must give to the immigration officer.
这些必须交给移民官。
Great.
很好。
So what is the opposite of arrival card?
那么入境卡的反义词是什么？
What do you fill out when you leave America?
离开美国时填什么？
That's right.
没错。
Some countries require you to fill out a departure card.
有些国家要求你填写出境卡。
All right.
好的。
So some countries, not all, but you'll usually get an arrival card, which means that you
所以有些国家，不是所有，但你通常会拿到入境卡，这意味着你
have to give your name and basic information.
必须提供姓名和基本信息。
That's right.
没错。
So we are talking to the immigration officer, and he asks, is this your country of birth
所以我们正在和移民官对话，他问，这是你的出生国
or residence?
或居住国吗？
All right, let's break that down.
好的，我们来分解一下。
Country of birth.
出生国。
So birth, birthday, that makes me think of where I was born.
所以出生，生日，这让我想到我出生的地方。
So what country were you born in?
你出生在哪个国家？
That's another way to ask this question.
这是问这个问题的另一种方式。
That's right.
没错。
So since we said we are coming from China, the immigration officer wants to know if we
既然我们说是从中国来的，移民官想知道我们
are Chinese or if we simply live there, and that's why he says or residence.
是中国人还是只是住在那里，所以他问“或居住国”。
So residence, it's a noun, it's a thing.
所以居住国，它是一个名词，是一个事物。
My country of residence is the place where I live.
我的居住国是我住的地方。
So I'm American, but maybe my country of residence is France because I live in France.
所以我是美国人，但我的居住国可能是法国，因为我住在法国。
That's right.
没错。
So it's different from your country of birth.
所以这和你的出生国不同。
Now moving on, when the immigration officer was asking us about money, we said that we
现在继续，当移民官问我们关于钱的问题时，我们说我们
have some traveler's checks and two credit cards.
有一些旅行支票和两张信用卡。
All right, so credit cards are pretty clear, but what exactly are traveler's checks and
好的，信用卡很清楚，但旅行支票到底是什么，
how are they different from normal checks?
和普通支票有什么不同？
So traveler's checks are kind of a convenient way to carry money because you have these
所以旅行支票是一种方便的携带钱的方式，因为你有这些
little pieces of paper that have a certain amount on them.
小纸片，上面有固定金额。
So for example, $500 each, and if you lose it, it's not a problem because no one can
比如，每张500美元，如果你丢了，也没问题，因为没人能
exchange those checks for cash unless it's you.
除非是你本人，否则不能把这些支票兑换成现金。
All right, so my traveler's check, I buy these from the bank.
好的，所以我的旅行支票是从银行买的。
They have my name on them, my passport number on them, and to spend them as money, I need
上面有我的名字和护照号码，要把它当钱花，我需要
to show my passport or proof of identification or proof of identity.
出示我的护照或身份证明。
So basically, if someone steals my traveler's checks, if I lose my traveler's checks, I
所以基本上，如果有人偷了我的旅行支票，或者我弄丢了旅行支票，我
don't have to worry because no one else can spend them but me.
不用担心，因为除了我没人能用它们。
Exactly.
没错。
They were very, very popular back before credit cards were so popular.
在信用卡普及之前，旅行支票非常流行。
Now you don't really see too many traveler's checks, but it's still convenient.
现在你不太常见到旅行支票了，但它仍然很方便。
All right, so a lot of language there.
好的，这里有很多语言点。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue again?
我们不如再听一遍对话吧？
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Passport and arrival card, please.
请出示护照和入境卡。
Here you are.
给你。
Where are you coming from?
你从哪里来？
China.
中国。
Is this your country of birth or residence?
这是你的出生国或居住国吗？
I just worked there.
我只是在那里工作。
What is the purpose of your visit to the United States?
你来美国的目的什么？
I'm here on vacation.
我来度假。
How long do you plan to stay in the United States?
你计划在美国待多久？
Almost three weeks.
差不多三周。
Sir, you didn't fill out the information on your arrival card of where you'll be staying.
先生，你没有在入境卡上填写你将要住的地方的信息。
Oh, I'm sorry, but there are a couple of different places I will travel to within the United
哦，对不起，但我在美国会去几个不同的地方旅行，
States, so I wasn't sure what to put.
所以我不确定该填什么。
You must specify an address on the place where you will spend most of your time.
你必须指定一个地址，是你大部分时间会待的地方。
Okay.
好的。
Here you are.
给你。
Do you have enough means to support yourself while you're here?
你在这里有足够的经济来源支持自己吗？
Yes, I have some traveler's checks and two credit cards.
是的，我有一些旅行支票和两张信用卡。
Very good.
很好。
Do you have anything to declare?
你有什么要申报的吗？
Nope.
没有。
I only have my clothes and camera.
我只有衣服和相机。
Very well, sir.
很好，先生。
Welcome to the United States.
欢迎来到美国。
Enjoy your visit.
祝你旅途愉快。
All right, we're back.
好的，我们回来了。
So now let's take a look at some of those key questions that the immigration officer
现在让我们看看移民官在流利度构建器中问的一些关键问题。
asks us on Fluency Builder.
流利度构建器。
Fluency Builder.
All right, this first sentence, this first question is actually something that a lot
好的，这第一句话，第一个问题，实际上是很多英语学习者觉得难的地方。
of learners of English have a hard time with.
你从哪里来？
Where are you coming from?
Right.
对。
So the immigration officer is sitting there at his desk and you are arriving on an airplane.
所以移民官坐在他的桌子后面，而你正从飞机上到达。
So what he wants to know is what country are you arriving from?
他想知道的是你从哪个国家到达？
So if I am on a flight from France to America, I say I'm arriving from France.
所以如果我坐从法国到美国的航班，我会说我从法国到达。
I'm coming from France.
我从法国来。
That's right.
没错。
But here's a big thing.
但这里有个重点。
What if he says, where are you from?
如果他说，你是哪里人？
Now he's asking you for your nationality.
那他是在问你的国籍。
So then you wouldn't say France because you're not French.
所以你不会说法国，因为你不是法国人。
I'm not French.
我不是法国人。
I'm American.
我是美国人。
So I'd say I am American, but I'm coming from France.
所以我会说我是美国人，但我从法国来。
So this is a very typical question that English learners confuse because as you can see, it's
这是一个英语学习者经常混淆的典型问题，因为你看，它
very, very similar, but you just have one word that you add on and it completely changes
非常非常相似，但只是加了一个词，就完全改变了
the question.
问题的意思。
So when the immigration officer asks you, where are you coming from?
所以当移民官问你，你从哪里来？
You tell them what country you got on the plane.
你告诉他们你上飞机的国家。
All right.
好的。
So where did you leave to come to America?
所以你从哪里出发来美国？
Did you leave from France, China, Ghana?
你是从法国、中国、加纳出发的吗？
So that's the answer to that question.
那就是这个问题的答案。
Exactly.
没错。
Most of the time, immigration officers will never ask you where you are from because they
大多数时候，移民官不会问你是哪里人，因为他们
will see your passport.
会看你的护照。
They know.
他们知道。
So, okay.
所以，好的。
Now, once we give them our passport, we tell them that we just work in China.
现在，一旦我们给他们护照，我们告诉他们我们只是在中国工作。
We're not Chinese.
我们不是中国人。
He asks, what is the purpose of your visit to the United States?
他问，你来美国的目的什么？
What's the purpose of your visit?
你来访的目的是什么？
Now purpose means goal or aim.
目的意思是目标或意图。
So there are a couple of standard answers to this question, but basically the immigration
这个问题有几个标准答案，但基本上移民官
officer wants to know, why are you in America?
想知道，你为什么来美国？
Why are you coming here?
你为什么来这里？
That's right.
没错。
So you have, as Catherine says, a couple of different ways of answering that.
所以，正如Catherine所说，你有几种不同的方式来回答这个问题。
We're saying here that we are here on vacation.
我们在这里是说，我们是来度假的。
I'm here on vacation.
我来这儿度假。
Tourism.
旅游。
Business.
商业。
Right.
好的。
Seeing family.
和家人见面。
These are all acceptable answers.
这些都是可以接受的答案。
That's right.
没错。
So now that we've told the officer all of this information, we actually forgot to fill
既然我们已经把所有这些信息都告诉了警官，我们实际上忘了填写
out our address on our arrival card.
在我们的入境卡上写上地址。
So he says that we must specify an address.
所以他说我们必须指定一个地址。
All right.
好的。
So to specify, this is a verb.
所以具体来说，这是一个动词。
It means to indicate or write down or identify because right now there is no address where
它的意思是标明、写下或识别，因为现在还没有地址。
we're going to stay.
我们要留下来。
So to specify means to basically to tell someone where it is, to be exact.
所以，"specify" 基本上就是告诉别人具体位置，要精确。
That's right.
没错。
So you need to specify an address of where you will be during the time you're in the
所以你需要指定一个你在美国期间将要居住的地址。
United States.
美国。
It could be a hotel, any place.
可以是酒店，任何地方。
Right.
对。
But it can't be like Chicago.
但不能只写芝加哥。
Right.
对。
No, it can't be a city.
不，不能只写城市。
It's got to be an address.
必须是一个具体地址。
Address.
地址。
So 10 South Street, Chicago, Illinois.
比如伊利诺伊州芝加哥市南街10号。
That's right.
没错。
Now we told the immigration officer where we're going to be and he asks a very important
现在我们告诉了移民官我们要去哪里，他问了一个非常重要的问题，
question, also very, very common.
也非常非常常见。
Do you have enough means to support yourself while you are here?
你是否有足够的经济能力来支持自己在这里的生活？
So means in this instance means resources or money.
所以这里的“means”指的是资源或金钱。
So do you have enough money to pay for your housing, your food?
也就是说，你是否有足够的钱支付住宿和食物？
That's the question.
这就是问题所在。
Right.
对。
So means to support yourself.
所以“means to support yourself”。
That means can you pay for yourself?
意思是你能否自己负担开销？
Who's paying for this trip?
这次旅行谁付钱？
Exactly.
没错。
So this is why we say, yeah, we have some traveler's checks and a couple of credit cards.
所以这就是为什么我们说，嗯，我们有一些旅行支票和几张信用卡。
And lastly, we also need to answer if we have anything to declare.
最后，我们还需要回答是否有东西要申报。
But what does this mean?
但这到底是什么意思？
To declare what?
申报什么？
To declare at customs.
在海关申报。
Okay.
好的。
But we don't normally ask to declare at customs.
但我们通常不会问“在海关申报”这种说法。
We just say, do you have anything to declare?
我们只是说，你有东西要申报吗？
This is because normally when we travel to other countries, there are special taxes for
这是因为通常当我们去其他国家旅行时，某些商品会有
certain goods.
特殊关税。
For example, if I want to come to America and I have three bottles of wine, I have to
例如，如果我想来美国，并且我有三瓶酒，我必须
give one away because I'm only allowed to bring in two bottles.
交出一瓶，因为我只允许带两瓶进来。
Right.
对。
So I have to declare two bottles of wine or money.
所以我必须申报两瓶酒或钱。
I'm only allowed to bring $10,000.
我只允许带一万美元。
If I bring $15,000, I have to write that down and say, I have this extra money and then
如果我带了一万五千美元，我必须写下来并说，我有这些额外的钱，然后
I pay tax.
我交税。
So basically they will ask you, what are you bringing to America?
所以基本上他们会问你，你带什么来美国？
And if there are special things like money or things you will sell or alcohol, cigarettes,
如果有特殊物品，比如钱、要出售的东西、酒或香烟，
you have to declare these.
你必须申报这些。
You have to explain what you're carrying.
你必须说明你携带了什么。
That's right.
没错。
So this is a very important question.
所以这是一个非常重要的问题。
Also most of the time, obviously if you're on tourism, you don't have much to declare,
另外大多数情况下，显然如果你是来旅游的，没什么需要申报，
but maybe like if Catherine says, maybe you are going to buy a house in the United States
但也许像凯瑟琳说的，你可能要去美国买房子，
and you have $20,000 in your luggage, then you need to tell them that.
而且行李里有两万美元，那你就得告诉他们。
That's right.
没错。
So that's called declaring, to declare at customs.
这就叫申报，在海关申报。
All right.
好的。
So let's take a break and listen to our dialogue one last time.
那我们休息一下，最后再听一遍对话。
Good afternoon.
下午好。
Passport and arrival card, please.
请出示护照和入境卡。
Here you are.
给你。
Where are you coming from?
你从哪里来？
China.
中国。
Is this your country of birth or residence?
这是你的出生国或居住国吗？
I just worked there.
我只是在那里工作过。
What is the purpose of your visit to the United States?
你来美国的目的是什么？
I'm here on vacation.
我来这儿度假。
How long do you plan to stay in the United States?
你计划在美国待多久？
Almost three weeks.
差不多三周。
Sir, you didn't fill out the information on your arrival card of where you'll be staying.
先生，您没有填写入境卡上关于您住宿地点的信息。
Oh, I'm sorry, but there are a couple of different places I will travel to within the United
哦，抱歉，但我在美国会去几个不同的地方旅行，
States, so I wasn't sure what to put.
所以我不确定该填什么。
You must specify an address on the place where you will spend most of your time.
您必须指定一个地址，即您大部分时间会待的地方。
Okay.
好的。
Here you are.
给您。
Do you have enough means to support yourself while you're here?
您有足够的经济能力支持您在这里的生活吗？
Yes, I have some traveler's checks and two credit cards.
是的，我有一些旅行支票和两张信用卡。
Very good.
很好。
Do you have anything to declare?
您有什么要申报的吗？
Nope.
没有。
I only have my clothes and camera.
我只有我的衣服和相机。
Very well, sir.
好的，先生。
Welcome to the United States.
欢迎来到美国。
Enjoy your visit.
祝您旅途愉快。
All right.
好的。
So when you're arriving to immigration, obviously all these questions are very, very common.
所以当你到达移民局时，显然这些问题都非常、非常常见。
You will be asked.
你会被问到的。
But when you're arriving there, there are actually two different sections that you have
但当你到达那里时，实际上有两个不同的区域你需要
to go to, right?
去，对吧？
That's right.
没错。
There's two different lines.
有两条不同的队伍。
Maybe many lines, but they'll have a sign on top.
可能有很多条队伍，但上面会有指示牌。
One says US passports or US passport holders, and that means the line for Americans coming
一个写着“美国护照”或“美国护照持有者”，那是给回美国的美国人排的队。
home to America.
回家到美国。
But for most people who are traveling to America, they're foreigners, they have to go to the
但对于大多数去美国旅行的人来说，他们是外国人，必须去
other line.
另一条队伍。
So that's non-US passport holders.
那就是非美国护照持有者。
That's right.
没错。
Now remember that you don't really have to get nervous when you're talking to the immigration
记住，当你和移民官交谈时，真的不必紧张。
officer.
官员。
You have to take it easy and just try to answer the questions.
你要放轻松，尽量回答问题。
Most of them will speak a couple of words in many popular languages like Chinese or
他们大多数人会说几种流行语言的几个词，比如中文或
Spanish or Arabic.
西班牙语或阿拉伯语。
Because obviously some people that go on holiday to the United States, maybe they don't speak
因为显然有些去美国度假的人可能不会说
English.
英语。
That's right.
没错。
So there's nothing to be worried about.
所以没什么好担心的。
These people are there to make sure that America is safe.
这些人在那里是为了确保美国的安全。
They want to check the bags.
他们想检查行李。
They want to know who's coming into the country.
他们想知道谁进入了这个国家。
And they're just doing their job being basically policing the borders.
他们只是在做本职工作，基本上是在边境执法。
But it's pretty simple.
但这很简单。
The most annoying part of customs for me is waiting in line.
对我来说，海关最烦人的部分就是排队等候。
Yeah, you have so many people arrive at the same time that you can wait in line maybe
是啊，这么多人同时到达，你可能要排队等
an hour sometimes.
有时一个小时。
Sometimes.
有时。
So again, just be honest.
所以再说一次，只要诚实就好。
And I think people will try to understand you if you're having a hard time.
而且我觉得如果你遇到困难，人们会试着理解你。
Exactly.
没错。
So if you have any questions or comments, you can find us at EnglishPod.com.
所以如果你有任何问题或评论，可以在EnglishPod.com找到我们。
And we'll see you guys there.
我们会在那里见你们。
Bye.
再见。